Fuad Babayev

Frontend Developer

Baku

<u>babayevffuad@gmail.com</u> +(994) 50 743 19 51 https://babayevfuad.com https://github.com/FuadBabayev https://www.linkedin.com/in/fuad-babayev-b8a649199

Summary

Web developer with more than two years of experience in Frontend Development. As a winner of Career Development Scholarship Program organized by Technest and Code Academy, I have successfully completed "Advanced Frontend Development" program with Honour Diploma. During education, I have contributed to several projects, ranging from e-commerce to admin dashboard systems, where I gained extensive knowledge of Figma, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, GSAP, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React, and Redux on the client side and MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Postman, NodeJS and PHP on the server side.

Experience

Frontend Developer — Proweb Creative Agency

June 2024 - Present

As I began my career as a Junior Frontend Developer, I specialize in creating responsive, user-friendly, and interactive real projects and make changes to existing sites. And all of the real-world projects featured in my portfolio.

My key responsibilities include:

- Developing responsive and accessible interfaces using HTML, CSS, and SCSS.
- Designing mobile-friendly layouts using CSS Grid, Flexbox, and Media Queries.
- Building dynamic and interactive components with JavaScript, TypeScript, and React.
- Adding animations, DOM manipulations, and form validation to enhance user experience
- Managing version control and team collaboration with Git and GitHub.

Frontend Developer Internship — GI Group

May 2024 – July 2024

- Creating the user interface and user experience (UI/UX) for Customer Relationship Management (CRM) systems using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React
- Participate in agile development processes, such as sprint planning and daily stand-ups
- Partner with designers, backend developers, and product managers to bring features from concept to implementation

Frontend Developer Mentor — Evocoding Training Center

Oct 2023 – Dec 2023

I continued as a mentor at Evocoding Training Center after completing my studies with a high average. In my role as a mentor, I improved my ability to communicate with students and how to solve difficult problems for them. For me, teaching the new students was a positive experience.

Frontend Developer Internship — AZ Tech IT Solution

Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

- Created multiple responsive websites for mobile and desktop devices using HTML and CSS, as well as third-party libraries of JavaScript such as Query, and React
- Increasing my ability to operate as a team by closely collaborating with twelve other students
- Working with REST API using Postman

Academic advisor — Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry

May 2021 – June 2022

- Monitor students' attendance and progress
- Assist students to become independent and collaborative learners
- Guidance of up to 100 undergraduate students

Achievements & Certificates

Career Development Scholarship at Code Academy

Dec 2023 – May 2024

Honour Diploma of Completion Advanced Frontend Development

Evocoding Training Center

June 2023 - Nov 2023

Certificate of Completion Front End Development

International Development Program (IDP)

Dec 2019 – Feb 2020

IELTS Score: 6.5/9

Additional Information

Languages: Azerbaijani (native), Turkish (native), English (intermediate),

German (pre-intermediate), Russian (pre-intermediate)

Frontend Development Tools: Figma, Git, Github, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap,

Tailwind CSS, GSAP, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React, Router, Redux **Backend Development Tools:** PHP, NodeJS, Express JS, Postman **Relational Database Management System:** SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL

NoSQL Database: Mongo DB, Mongoose

Education

Advanced Frontend Development

Dec 2023 - May 2024

Career Development Scholarship Program | Technest and Code Academy

Master of Science

Sep 2020 – July 2022

Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University | Research and Exploration of Oil and Gas fields.

Bachelor of Science

Sep 2016 – July 2020

French-Azerbaijani University | Geophysical Engineering